Guide to the Katja B. Goldman and Michael Sonnenfeldt Collection of Photographs 1900-2002 PR 305
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: New York Theatre, 1900-1937; 58318
  Subseries I.2, Theatrical Stage Sets, encompasses tableau photography of production sets including Naughty Cinderella (1925), featuring the costume and scenic design of preeminent fashion designer Paul Poiret.
  Subseries I.3, Theatrical Portraits, consists of individual studio portraits and production photographs labelled by performer. Worldwide star Maude Adams joins recurrently depicted performers Dorothy Gish, Minna Gombell, Edna Hibbard, Mary Howard, Francine Larrimore, Margaret Lawrence, Margaret Lee, Bruce McRae, and others.
  While narrative musical productions are included in the first subseries, images of vaudeville, comedy, and music performers, acts, ensembles, and dance numbers have been separately filed in Subseries I.4, Musical Revues, Dance and Vaudeville. Subjects include landmark productions Floradora and Roberta; revue shows presented by leading impresarios George M. Cohan, George White, Billy Rose, Earl Carroll, and Irving Berlin; Florence Ziegfeld's Follies and other productions at the Winter Garden and New Amsterdam Theatre; Happy Days, The Wars of the World, and other large-scale productions at the New York Hippodrome; and an unidentified 1911 image labelled "First Tango on American Stage." Individual portraits feature sitters billed as vaudevillians, dancers, singers, and other novely acts including many Ziegfeld and Earl Carroll "Follies Girls" such as Lulu McConnell, film and gossip column star Geneva Mitchell, and Princess White Deer.
  Images throughout this series are often stamped with photographer's credit and variously include subject name, date, and other information. Some photographs also feature publicity captions on the verso. A small selection of photographs have been laminated, and are housed separately, as depicted in the container list.
  Arrangement
  Within each series, images are arranged alphabetically by the name of the production or performer depicted. Productions or people represented by a single image have been grouped together and filed alphabetically in "Miscellaneous" files; productions or people depicted in multiple images have been foldered separately and specifically identified in the container list.
  Additional Theatrical Production shots and Theatrical Portraits are included in Series IV and Series VI.
  - Subseries I.1: Theatrical Productions, 1900-1937; 58321
    - "A" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 59437 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
    - The Acquittal, 1920; 59438 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - The Awful Truth, 1922; 59439 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "B" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 59440 (Box 1, Folder 9-12)
    - "C" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 59441 (Box 1, Folder 13-17)
    - Casanova, 1923; 59442 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Cloudy With Showers, 1931; 59444 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Coquette, 1927; 59443 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Counsellor at Law, 1931; 59445 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Countess Martiza, 1928; 59535 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Cousin Billy, 1905; 59446 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "D" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 59447 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
    - The Dancer, 1919; 59450 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Dancing Partners, 1930; 59448 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - The Dove, 1925; 59449 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Dodsworth, 1934; 59451 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - "E" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 59452 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "F" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 59453 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
    - "G" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 59454 (Box 2, Folder 11-22)
    - Gamblers All, 1917; 59468 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - The Girl from Montmarte, 1912; 59455 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The Girl Who Smiles, 1915; 59456 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - The Gold Diggers, 1919; 59457 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Good Boy, 1928; 59458 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Good Bad Woman, 1925; 59459 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Go To It, 1916; 59460 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Going Up, 1917; 59461 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - The Great Divide, 1906; 59462 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - The Great Power, 1928; 59463 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Grounds for Divorce, 1924; 59464 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - The Guilty Man, 1916; 59465 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The Guilty One, 1923; 59466 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Gypsy, 1929; 59467 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "H" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 59469 (Box 3, Folder 9-17)
    - Half an Hour, 1926; 59470 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Happy Husbands, 1928; 59472 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
    - Harvest Moon, 1909; 59471 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Heavy Traffic, 1928; 59473 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
    - Held by the Enemy, 1910; 59474 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Hello Alexander, 1919; 59475 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Her Master's Voice, 1933; 59476 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Here Comes the Bride, 1917; 59477 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Here Today, 1932; 59478 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - High Cost of Living, 1916; 59479 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - The High Road, 1928; 59480 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - High Tor, 1937; 59481 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Hobson's Choice, 1915; 59482 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Honey Girl, 1920; 59483 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "I" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 59484 (Box 4, Folder 13-17)
    - In His Arms, 1924; 59485 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Inside the Lines, 1915; 59486 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Indian Summer, 1913; 59487 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Innocent, 1914; 59488 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Interference, 1927; 59489 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - The Intruder, 1916; 59490 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Iole, 1913; 59491 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Isobel, 1925; 59492 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "J" - Miscellaenous, 1900-1937; 59493 (Box 5, Folder 4-6)
    - Janice Meredith, 1900; 59494 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Josephine, 1918; 59495 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Johnny Get Your Gun, 1917; 59496 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - June Moon, 1929; 59497 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Just A Woman, 1916; 59498 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Just A Minute, 1928; 59499 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "K" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 59500 (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
    - The Kiss Burglar, 1918; 59501 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Kissing Time, 1918; 59502 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Kitty Mackay, 1914; 59503 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "L" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 59504 (Box 6, Folder 1-7)
    - The Left Bank, 1931; 59505 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Little Accident, 1928; 59506 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Little Simplicity, 1918; 59507 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Little Lady Blue, 1916; 59508 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - The Little Teacher, 1918; 59509 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Little Women, 1931; 59510 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Loose Ends, 1926; 59511 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Loyalties, 1922; 59512 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - The Lure, 1913; 59513 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - "M" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 59514 (Box 7, Folder 1-10)
    - Main Street, 1921; 59515 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - The Marriage of Columbine, 1914; 59516 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Mary, 1920; 59517 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - The Masquerader, 1917; 59518 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - The Master, 1916; 59519 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - The Melody of Youth, 1916; 59520 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - A Message from Mars, 1901; 59521 (Box 7, Folder 16-18)
    - Mile-A-Minute Kendall, 1916; 59522 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Minick, 1924; 59523 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - The Miracle Man, 1914; 59524 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Misalliance, 1917; 59525 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Misleading Lady, 1913; 61373 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - The Moon-Flower, 1924; 59526 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "N" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 61374 (Box 8, Folder 3-7)
    - Nearly Married, 1913; 59527 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - The New York Idea, 1915; 61375 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - The Ninety and Nine, 1902; 59528 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - No. 13 Washington Square, 1915; 61376 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Nothing But the Truth, 1916; 59529 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - "O" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 61377 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - "P" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 61378 (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
    - Polly With A Past, 1917; 59530 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - "R" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 61379 (Box 8, Folder 15-16)
    - "S" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 61380 (Box 8, Folder 17-20)
    - The Saving Grace, 1918; 59531 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - Spring Song, 1934; 59532 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
    - "T" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 61381 (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
    - "U" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 61382 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "V" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 61383 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "W" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 61384 (Box 9, Folder 8-11)
    - Why Marry, 1917; 59533 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Whispering Wires, 1923; 61385 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - "Y" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 61386 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified, 1900-1935; 61387 (Box 9, Folder 14-15)
    - "A-H" - Miscellaneous - Laminated, 1900-1937; 59534 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - "J-M" - Miscellaneous - Laminated, 61898 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - "M-W" - Miscellaneous - Laminated, 61899 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Subseries I.2: Theatrical Stage Sets, 1900-1937; 58493
    - "A-Z" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 61395 (Box 9, Folder 16-17)
    - The Girl from Montmarte, 1912; 61396 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Indian Summer, 1913; 61397 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Naughty Cinderella, 1925; 61398 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Subseries I.3: Theatrical Portraits (Individual), 1904-1938, undated; 58494
    - "A" - Miscellaneous, 61399 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Maude Adams, 1904-1911; 61400 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - "B-F " - Miscellaneous, 61900 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Billie Burke, Undated; 61401 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Ina Claire, Undated; 61402 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Alfred Lunt and Lynn Fontanne, 1935-1938; 61403 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - "G" - Miscellaneous, 61901 (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
    - "H" - Miscellaneous, 61902 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
    - "I-J" - Miscellaneous, 61903 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "K" - Miscellaneous, 61904 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
    - "L" - Miscellaneous, 61905 (Box 10, Folder 5-7)
    - "M" - Miscellaneous, 61906 (Box 10, Folder 7-9)
    - "N-R" - Miscellaneous, 61907 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - "S-V" - Miscellaneous, 61908 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - "W" - Miscellaneous, 61909 (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
    - "B-F" - Miscellaneous - Laminated, 61910 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - "G-L" - Miscellaneous - Laminated, 61911 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - "L-M" - Miscellaneous - Laminated, 61912 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - "M-W" - Miscellaneous - Laminated, 61913 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Subseries I.4: Musical Revues, Dance and Vaudeville, 1900-1937; 58495
    This subseries is further arranged into two subseries: A) Group Portraits and Production Stills (alphabetical by production or theatre) and B) Individual Portraits (alphabetical by sitter).
    - Subseries I.4. A: Group Portraits and Production Stills, 58497
      - "A-Z" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 61428 (Box 10, Folder 14-16)
      - Unknown, 1900-1937; Undated; 61429 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - New York Hippodrome, 1900-1937; 61430 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Winter Garden, 1900-1937; 61431 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Ziegfeld Follies, 1900-1937; 61432 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Subseries I.4. B: Individual Portraits, 58496
      - "A-C" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 61427 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - "D-G" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 73320 (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - "H-L" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 73321 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - "M" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 73322 (Box 10, Folder 21-23)
      - "N-P" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 73323 (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - "R-Z" - Miscellaneous, 1900-1937; 73324 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Series II: Hollywood Film, 1928-1944; 58319
  The Hollywood Film series represents the American film industry's publicity output from the late silent period into what is generally regarded as the "Golden Era" (between 1920 and 1960). In this period, the studios meticulously and rigorously controlled the image of their contracted stars, generating and distributing photographs to fans and publications.
  Special photography units were established at each studio to create publicity images of performers away from production sets and costumes. A majority of materials in this series represent this output; many are studio portraits but also present are candid and staged shots depicting subjects at home, with their families and friends, engaging in physical and outdoor activities, and performing beauty regimens. Photographs are variously labelled or stamped with sitter, production, original collection, date, studio, credit lines, and photographer; in some cases, original annotations and publicity captions are present.
  The work of the pioneer film portraitists depicted in the collection helped define careers and created a resonating iconography of Hollywood. Legendary and established stars appear in the collection alongside character actors, ingenues, and animal performers.
  Output from Clarence S. Bull and other in-house photographers of preeminent studio Metro Goldwyn Mayer comprises the first subseries. Recurring performers depicted in this subseries (1929-1943) are Lionel Barrymore, Wallace Beery, Walter Huston, Adolpe Menjou, Robert Montgomery, Maureen O'Sullivan, Mickey Rooney, Walter Pigeon, Rosalind Russell, Jimmy Stewart, and Robert Young. Select writers, directors (Rouben Mamoulian), and other crew are also present, as are the homes of Huston and Myrna Loy.
  The second subseries features work outside of Metro-Goldwyn Mayer and therefore comprises a wider range of image subjects, sitters, photographers, dates, and sources. All the major studios -- Warner Bros, Universal, Paramount, RKO, Fox Corporation, and Columbia Pictures -- as well as independents Republic Pictures and Selznick International are represented. Earlier subjects include silent stars Betty Compson, Hoot Gibson, Lew Cody, Wallace Reid, and Florence Vidor. Later iconic stars of the talkies Henry Fonda and Ginger Rogers appear recurrently in the collection, as do Jean Hersholt, Henry Hull, and the producer Joan Harrison. The work of Polish photographer Roman Freulich (1898-1974), of Universal and later Republic, is well represented. Other photographers featured include John Miehle (RKO, Selznick International), George Hurrell, George Hommel, and Gene Robert Richee.
  The Hollywood photographs are arranged by studio into two subseries. Each subseries is further arranged into: A) Individual Portraits (alphabetical by sitter) and B) Group Portraits and Production Stills (alphabetical by production). Group portraits in which a main star is emphasized are filed under Individual Portraits. Select subjects appear in both series.
  Within each subseries, images have been housed according to size (small format or large format); a few of the images have been laminated and separately housed. Accordingly, researchers looking for a particular performer or production may need to consult multiple folders within each subseries.
  Materials are often stamped with photographer's credit and variously include subject name, date, and other information. Some photographs also feature publicity captions on the verso.
  Additional Hollywood portraits are in Series IV and V.
  - Subseries II.1: MGM & Clarence S. Bull, 1929-1943; 58324
    Biographical / Historical
    Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM), advertised as the stable of "more stars than there are in Heaven," dominated the American movie industry in the 1930s. Its profits equalled three-quarters the total of the remaining Big Eight studios combined. Under the leadership of Louis B. Meyer and head of production Irving Thalberg, MGM enraptured Depression-era audiences with its dependable product of escapist glamour and sophistication.
    A central figure in the development of the MGM brand was Clarence Sinclair Bull (1886-1979), head of the stills department for over three decades, whose work comprises the majority of this subseries. As described by Hedda Hopper, actress and later gossip columnist who appears in the collection, Bull was "as much of a Metro institution as Leo the Lion."
    The son of a Montana cattle rancher, Bull initially sold his images as postcards out of the film printing and development studio he operated from his family's general store. Impressed customer Mrs. Frank Lloyd, wife of the famous film director, arranged for Bull's hiring as an assistant cameraman in Hollywood in 1917.
    Following work for several studios and a shift in concentration to still photography, Bull settled at Goldwyn Studios, which was amalgamated into MGM in 1924. Bull estimated that he photographed over 10,000 separate subjects in his career, and over 4,000 individual studies of Greta Garbo, in the collaboration for which he is most well-regarded. Garbo, notoriously shy and publicity-adverse, elected Bull as her sole personal photographer from 1929 onwards. Bull was also responsible for enhancing the image of all of MGM's stars, including favorite subjects Jean Harlow, Clark Gable, Gloria Swanson, Lon Chaney, the Barrymores, and later Katharine Hepburn, Robert Mitchum, and Elizabeth Taylor.
    In the mid-1950s, Bull was sent by the studio on his own publicity campaign, making television and radio appearances and speaking before camera clubs. Before his death in 1979, Bull was able to see his work commemorated and exhibited, and was bestowed the degree of Honorary Master by the Professional Photographers of America. "In portraits, " he said, "I have tried to capture a moment or mood unattainable with the motion picture camera."
    - Subseries II.1 A: Individual Portraits and Publicity, 58498
      - "B" - Miscellaneous - Small Format, 1929-1943; 61433 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - "C-G" - Miscellaneous - Small Format, 1929-1943; 61530 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - "H-M" - Miscellaneous - Small Format, 1929-1943; 61531 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - "N-P" - Miscellaneous - Small Format, 1929-1943; 61532 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - "R-S" - Miscellaneous - Small Format, 1929-1943; 61533 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - "T-Y" - Miscellaneous - Small Format, 1929-1943; 61534 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - "A-F" - Miscellaneous - Large Format, 1929-1943; 59606 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - "G-W" - Miscellaneous - Large Format, 1929-1943; 61535 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - "A-H" - Miscellaneous - Small Format - Laminated, 1929-1943; 59604 (Box 13)
      - "I-Z" - Miscellaneous - Small Format - Laminated, 1929-1943; 59605 (Box 14)
      - "A-Z" - Miscellaneous - Large Format - Laminated, 1929-1943; 61536 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Subseries II.1 B: Group Portraits and Publicity, 58499
      - "A-Z" - Miscellaneous - Small Format, 1929-1943; 59607 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - "A-Z" - Miscellaneous - Small Format - Laminated, 1929-1943; 59608 (Box 15)
      - "A-Z" - Miscellaneous - Large Format, 1929-1943; 61537 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Subseries II.2: Other Studios, 1928-1944; Undated; 58326
    - Subseries II.2 A: Individual Portraits and Publicity, 1928-1944; 58568
      - "A-F" - Miscellaneous - Small Format, 1928-1944; 59609 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - "G-P" - Miscellaneous - Small Format, 1928-1944; 61538 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - "R-Y" - Miscellaneous - Small Format, 1928-1944; 61539 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - "G-M" - Miscellaneous - Large Format, 1928-1944; 61540 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - "A-L" - Miscellaneous - Laminated, 1928-1944; 59610 (Box 17)
      - "M-Z" - Miscellaneous - Laminated, 1928-1944; 59611 (Box 18)
    - Subseries II.2 B: Group Portraits and Publicity, 1928-1944; 58569
      - A-Z, 59612
    - "A-Z" - Miscellaneous - Small Format, 1928-1944; 61509 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - "A-Z" - Miscellaenous - Large Format, 1928-1944; 61510 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - "A-Z" - Miscellaneous - Laminated, 1928-1944; 61388 (Box 18)
    - Unidentified - Small Format, 1928-1944; Undated; 59536 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Series III: Ken Regan and Camera 5, 1965-2002; 58320
  Photojournalist Ken Regan (d. 2012) worked for over five decades prolifically documenting pop culture, sports, foreign conflicts, and other current events. Credited with over 200 magazine covers, Regan was most well-known for a discretion and professionalism which earned him intimate shooting access to famous politicians, musicians, and other celebrities.
  Born in the Bronx, Regan received a camera for his 12th birthday and began shooting sports and musical events as the Mount Saint Michael Academy school photographer. He studied journalism at Columbia and attended New York University Film School. His first paid assignment, from the New York Times Sunday Magazine, was to cover the famous Thanksgiving rock concert at the Fillmore East featuring Jefferson Airplane and Johnny Winter; his work ultimately resulted in a three-page spread. Regan sent self-made prints of his work along with a thank you note to the concert promoter Bill Graham. This unusual practice, which he continued throughout his career, inaugurated a symbiotic relationship with Graham, who later established Regan as house photographer to The Rolling Stones and Bob Dylan.
  Regan also covered major sports events for magazines Time, Sports Illustrated, Life, and Newsweek. In the 1970s he founded Camera 5, an agency of 15 photographers who covered wars, riots and demonstrations, and other national and international hard news and human interest stories.
  In addition, Regan served as the self-proclaimed "unofficial Kennedy family photographer" for thirty years, amassing one of the largest bodies of photographs of the Camelot political dynasty in both public and private settings.
  Regan's work continually appeared in a wide range of major publications including Vanity Fair, Rolling Stone, and People, who often called upon Regan to capture unguarded moments from camera weary celebrities. "We trust him," musician James Taylor wrote of Regan in his 2011 publication of rock and roll photography All Access, "We can be ourselves around him. He is one of us." Regan additionally published Knockout: The Art of Boxing in 2007.
  Of his photography goals, Regan said "I think that if you're able to capture an image that nobody else has then that's what makes the image important; that's what people are interested in." Increased publicist control over celebrity access and the advent of digital photography reduced magazine travel assignments, prompting Regan's turn towards corporate film and television work in the 90s. He developed continuing working relationships with directors Jonathan Demme and Clint Eastwood, among others, for whom he shot on-set production photography. Regan died on November 25, 2012.
  The Ken Regan photographs are arranged into four main subseries: 1) On-Set Productions, 2) Portraiture, 3) New York Events, and 4) Dachau. Further arrangement is outlined in individual subseries notes.
  Materials are stamped as being the work of Ken Regan and property of Camera 5. Subject names, dates, and further descriptions inconsistently appear on the verso, with frequent name misspellings. Some of the photographs have been laminated, and are housed separately, as depicted in the container list.
  - Subseries III.1: On-Set Productions, 1970-2002; 58334
    This subseries features Regan's on-set photography work, chiefly on film and television productions, but also including the 1977 television broadcast of the National Ballet Theatre production of The Nutcracker, featuring Mikhail Baryshnikov and a Metropolitian opera production. Some early Regan work -- notably, John and Mary (1969) and Little Murders (1971) -- appears, but the series generally comprises Regan's corporate assignments from the 1990s and 2000s. These include recurring collaborations with directors Jonathan Demme and Clint Eastwood and actor Denzel Washington, substantial coverage of Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt in The Devil's Own (1997), and the chronicling of Christopher Reeve's directorial debut In the Gloaming (1997), two years after his paralysis.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by production title, with all featured productions identified in the container list.